<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://incodeks.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://incodeks.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-02-13T10:17:10-05:00</updated><id>http://incodeks.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Incodeks</title><subtitle>A Trusted, Talented, and Transparent Software Development Partner</subtitle><entry><title type="html">5 Ways Team Augmentation Can Help Your Business Scale</title><link href="http://incodeks.com/5-Ways-Team-Augmentation-Can-Help-Your-Business-Scale/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Ways Team Augmentation Can Help Your Business Scale" /><published>2023-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://incodeks.com/5%20Ways-Team-Augmentation-Can-Help-Your-Business-Scale</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://incodeks.com/5-Ways-Team-Augmentation-Can-Help-Your-Business-Scale/"><![CDATA[##### Introduction
 

Team augmentation is an increasingly popular way for businesses to grow and scale their operations. By outsourcing specific roles and tasks to specialized teams, businesses can achieve greater efficiency, flexibility, and scalability. In this blog post, we'll discuss five ways in which team augmentation can help your business scale and also showcase a company that specializes in engineering team augmentation, Incodeks.

1. Access to specialized skills and expertise: Team augmentation allows businesses to access specialized skills and expertise that they may not have in-house. For example, a company that specializes in software development may outsource a specific project to a team of experts in artificial intelligence or machine learning. This allows the company to achieve better results in less time, and to stay competitive in the market. Incodeks, for instance, has helped different clients with engineering team augmentation, providing them with top-notch engineers with specific skillsets to help them achieve their goals.

2. Increased flexibility and scalability: Team augmentation allows businesses to scale up or down their operations as needed, depending on the demands of the market. For example, a business that experiences a surge in demand for its products or services can quickly and easily scale up its operations by outsourcing specific tasks to a team of experts. Incodeks, with its flexible engagement models, can help businesses to scale up or down their engineering teams as per their needs.
  
3. Reduced overhead costs: By outsourcing specific roles and tasks to a team augmentation provider like Incodeks, businesses can reduce their overhead costs. This is because they don't need to invest in the infrastructure, equipment, and office space required to support in-house teams.
 
4. Improved work-life balance: Team augmentation allows businesses to outsource specific tasks to teams that work in different time zones. This can help businesses achieve a better work-life balance, as they don't need to work around the clock to meet the demands of the market. Incodeks, with its global delivery model, can help businesses to outsource their engineering teams to different time zones as per their needs.
 
5. Increased efficiency and productivity: Team augmentation allows businesses to focus on their core competencies, while outsourcing specific tasks to specialized teams. This can help businesses achieve greater efficiency and productivity, as they don't need to spend time and resources on tasks that are outside of their area of expertise. With Incodeks, businesses can rest assured that their engineering tasks are in the hands of experts, allowing them to focus on their core competencies.

In conclusion, team augmentation is a powerful tool that can help businesses grow and scale their operations. By outsourcing specific roles and tasks to specialized teams, businesses can achieve greater efficiency, flexibility, and scalability. With the right team augmentation provider like Incodeks, businesses can achieve their goals and stay competitive in the market. Incodeks has a proven track record of helping different clients with engineering team augmentation, and they can help your business too.]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Team augmentation is an increasingly popular way for businesses to grow and scale their operations. By outsourcing specific roles and tasks to specialized teams, businesses can achieve greater efficiency, flexibility, and scalability.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Pros and Cons of Outsourcing Specific Team Roles</title><link href="http://incodeks.com/pros-and-cons-outsourcing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Pros and Cons of Outsourcing Specific Team Roles" /><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://incodeks.com/pros-and-cons-outsourcing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://incodeks.com/pros-and-cons-outsourcing/"><![CDATA[##### Introduction

Outsourcing specific team roles has become an increasingly popular way for businesses to improve efficiency, reduce costs, and stay competitive in the market. However, like any business strategy, outsourcing has its advantages and disadvantages. In this blog post, we'll discuss the pros and cons of outsourcing specific team roles, provide examples of roles that are commonly outsourced, and the benefits that businesses can achieve by doing so. Also, we'll mention a trusted vendor in the outsourcing industry, Incodeks.

Pros:

1. Access to specialized skills and expertise: Outsourcing specific team roles allows businesses to access specialized skills and expertise that they may not have in-house. For example, a business that specializes in software development may outsource a specific project to a team of experts in artificial intelligence or machine learning. This allows the business to achieve better results in less time, and to stay competitive in the market. Incodeks, for instance, offers a wide range of outsourcing services, including engineering, design, and project management, which can help businesses to access specialized skills and expertise.
2. Increased flexibility and scalability: Outsourcing specific team roles allows businesses to scale up or down their operations as needed, depending on the demands of the market. For example, a business that experiences a surge in demand for its products or services can quickly and easily scale up its operations by outsourcing specific tasks to a team of experts. Incodeks, with its flexible engagement models, can help businesses to scale up or down their teams as per their needs.
3. Reduced overhead costs: By outsourcing specific team roles to a provider like Incodeks, businesses can reduce their overhead costs. This is because they don't need to invest in the infrastructure, equipment, and office space required to support in-house teams.
4. Improved work-life balance: Outsourcing specific team roles allows businesses to outsource specific tasks to teams that work in different time zones. This can help businesses achieve a better work-life balance, as they don't need to work around the clock to meet the demands of the market. Incodeks, with its global delivery model, can help businesses to outsource their teams to different time zones as per their needs.

Cons:

1. Loss of control: Outsourcing specific team roles can lead to a loss of control over the work that's being done. This can be especially problematic if the outsourced team is working on a critical project or task. However, with a trusted vendor like Incodeks, businesses can have a clear communication, regular status updates and defined processes in place to minimize the risk of loss of control.
2. Communication barriers: Outsourcing specific team roles can lead to communication barriers, as the outsourced team may not be located in the same place as the rest of the business. However, Incodeks ensures that there is regular communication and coordination between the client and the outsourced team, through various communication tools and platforms.
3. Quality issues: Outsourcing specific team roles can lead to quality issues, as the outsourced team may not have the same level of expertise or experience as an in-house team. But, Incodeks has a rigorous recruitment process, and they only hire highly skilled and experienced professionals to ensure the highest quality of work.
4. Dependency on third party: Outsourcing specific team roles can lead to dependency on a third party, which can be problematic if the third party fails to deliver the work on time or to the quality expected. Incodeks, with its transparent and efficient processes, ensures timely delivery of projects and maintains a high level of quality, minimizing the risk of dependency on a third party.

Examples of Roles that are commonly outsourced:

1. IT and software development
2. Human resources
3. Customer service
4. Marketing and advertising
5. Logistics and fulfillment
6. Finance and accounting
7. Legal services

In conclusion, outsourcing specific team roles can be a powerful tool for businesses looking to improve efficiency, reduce costs, and stay competitive in the market. However, it's important to weigh the pros and cons and to carefully consider the roles that are being outsourced. By choosing the right provider, businesses can achieve the benefits of outsourcing while minimizing the risks and drawbacks. Incodeks is a trusted, talented and transparent partner in the outsourcing industry, with a proven track record of helping businesses achieve their goals through outsourcing specific team roles.

###### About Incodeks
<p>
Located in Ferizaj, Prishtina and San Francisco, Incodeks is a software engineering company specialising in the development and maintenance of mobile and web applications, Artificial Intelligence (Chat & Voice bots) and other dedicated services. Given that we guide our clients through the entire process and life-cycle, Incodeks uses the Agile methodology which enables us to increase efficiency in project management and deliver desirable results within an estimated timeframe. Some of the various technologies we use include: Python, JavaScript, PHP, CSS, HTML, Laravel, React Native, REACTJS, Bootstrap, etc. Besides artificial intelligence, we deeply honour the value in emotional and human intelligence presented by our dedicated teammates. Cultivating a healthy, joyful working environment fuels our mission towards establishing a successful, long-lasting partnership with one another. Join a collaborative and supportive team that continuously learns and grows together towards a common goal- creating a better, progressive future for everyone.
</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Outsourcing specific team roles has become an increasingly popular way for businesses to improve efficiency, reduce costs, and stay competitive in the market.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Team Augmentation is the Future of Work</title><link href="http://incodeks.com/Team-Augmentation-Future-Of-Work/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Team Augmentation is the Future of Work" /><published>2022-09-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-09-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://incodeks.com/Team-Augmentation-Future-Of-Work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://incodeks.com/Team-Augmentation-Future-Of-Work/"><![CDATA[The way businesses operate is constantly evolving, and the rise of team augmentation is a testament to that. Team augmentation is becoming an increasingly popular way for companies to manage their workforce and stay competitive in the market. In this blog post, we'll discuss how team augmentation is changing the way businesses operate and why it's becoming the future of work.

1. Access to specialized skills and expertise: Team augmentation allows businesses to access specialized skills and expertise that they may not have in-house. For example, a company that specializes in software development may outsource a specific project to a team of experts in artificial intelligence or machine learning. This allows the company to achieve better results in less time, and to stay competitive in the market.

2. Increased flexibility and scalability: Team augmentation allows businesses to scale up or down their operations as needed, depending on the demands of the market. For example, a business that experiences a surge in demand for its products or services can quickly and easily scale up its operations by outsourcing specific tasks to a team of experts.

3. Reduced overhead costs: By outsourcing specific roles and tasks to a team augmentation provider, businesses can reduce their overhead costs. This is because they don't need to invest in the infrastructure, equipment, and office space required to support in-house teams.

4. Improved work-life balance: Team augmentation allows businesses to outsource specific tasks to teams that work in different time zones. This can help businesses achieve a better work-life balance, as they don't need to work around the clock to meet the demands of the market.

5. Increased efficiency and productivity: Team augmentation allows businesses to focus on their core competencies, while outsourcing specific tasks to specialized teams. This can help businesses achieve greater efficiency and productivity, as they don't need to spend time and resources on tasks that are outside of their area of expertise.

Team augmentation is changing the way businesses operate, and it's becoming an increasingly popular way for companies to manage their workforce. It allows businesses to stay competitive in the market, improve efficiency and productivity, and reduce costs. InCodeks, for instance, is implementing the best and coherent practices when it comes to team augmentation, providing businesses with top-notch engineers with specific skillsets and flexible engagement models to help them achieve their goals.

In conclusion, team augmentation is the future of work, and it's a powerful tool that can help businesses grow and scalea]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The way businesses operate is constantly evolving, and the rise of team augmentation is a testament to that.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Incodeks’ CEO, Partin Imeri, attends the First Conference by Albanian Developers</title><link href="http://incodeks.com/albanian-developers-conference/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Incodeks’ CEO, Partin Imeri, attends the First Conference by Albanian Developers" /><published>2022-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://incodeks.com/albanian-developers-conference</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://incodeks.com/albanian-developers-conference/"><![CDATA[##### Introduction

<img src="/assets/posts/partin-imeri-albanian-developer-conference-photo-1-min.jpg" style="width: 100%;height: 400px; object-fit:contain;object-position: left">

The weekend we left behind was followed by the first conference by Albanian Developers, where we marked our participation through the Executive Director of Incodeks, Partin Imeri.<br><br>
<img src="/assets/posts/partin-imeri-albanian-developer-conference-photo-2.jpg" style="width: 100%;height: 400px; object-fit:contain;object-position: left">
<br>

Together with other panellists, Partin Imeri discussed in front of the audience about Web3, a technology that is shaping the future and the digital society. Web3 is considered as one of the pillars of the digital future and the technological revolution. Incodeks has already integrated Web 3.0 technologies into innovative products and services, and through the Albanian Developers conference a discussion space was provided to elaborate and further share with the IT community about them.

<img src="/assets/posts/albanian-developer-conference-photo-1-min.jpg" style="width: 100%;height: 400px; object-fit:contain;object-position: left">

<foto>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The weekend we left behind was followed by the first conference by Albanian Developers, where we marked our participation through the Executive Director of Incodeks, Partin Imeri.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Incodeks mentors the “Coding Day” event hosted by Universum College</title><link href="http://incodeks.com/coding-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Incodeks mentors the “Coding Day” event hosted by Universum College" /><published>2021-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://incodeks.com/coding-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://incodeks.com/coding-day/"><![CDATA[##### Introduction

On March 22nd, Incodeks once again proved its commitment to the Tech Industry by offering young Computer Science students the opportunity to practice their coding skills under the mentorship of our professionals. 
<br><br>
Modern educational institutions, especially higher education, preach practical teaching and learning, which involves a wide and diverse range of activities that meet student interests. The main purpose of these activities is complementing the academic curriculum as well as enhancing students’ skills by simulating real life situations that are most likely to appear throughout their career.
<br><br>
Following a few years of devoted collaboration, Incodeks contributed to the event by bringing internal IT and Software Engineering professionals who served as mentors to the young students. “Coding Day” was followed by a presentation to the industry, and proceeded with coding challenges to be completed by young students under the guidance of Incodeks’ professionals. 
<br><br>
<div style="display:flex;justify-content: space-between">
<img src="/assets/posts/universum.jpeg" style="width: 78%;height: 400px; object-fit:cover;">
<img src="/assets/posts/universum1.jpeg" style="width: 20%;height: 400px; object-fit:cover;">
</div>
<br><br>
To further support the involvement of young students and graduates into the labour market, Incodeks brought representatives from the Human Resources department to target driven potential candidates to conduct professional internships in the company. Being an intern is a valuable way to gain real-world experience outside of the classroom and have material to add to your resume. Incodeks representatives value the latter as guidance to one’s personal career goals and an opportunity to learn about the expectations of employment in the respective field.
<br><br>
<img src="/assets/posts/universum2.jpeg" style="width: 100%;height: 400px;margin:0 auto; object-fit:cover">
<br><br>
As a result, “Coding Day” wrapped up on a high satisfaction level by both parties; the hosting university, and the mentoring company- Incodeks. Foremost, witnessing young students exhibit the skills and dedication required of a future professional has been an enlightening experience. Our youth is considered as the greatest asset, and as such it is with great desire to invest time and effort into their development and well-being. Incodeks remains open and willing to engage in similar events and activities that fuel youth engagement and development, specifically in the ICT sector.
<br><br>
<img src="/assets/posts/universum.jpeg" style="width: 100%;height: 400px;margin:0 auto; object-fit:cover">
<br><br>

###### About Incodeks
<p>
Located in Ferizaj, Prishtina and San Francisco, Incodeks is a software engineering company specialising in the development and maintenance of mobile and web applications, Artificial Intelligence (Chat & Voice bots) and other dedicated services. Given that we guide our clients through the entire process and life-cycle, Incodeks uses the Agile methodology which enables us to increase efficiency in project management and deliver desirable results within an estimated timeframe. Some of the various technologies we use include: Python, JavaScript, PHP, CSS, HTML, Laravel, React Native, REACTJS, Bootstrap, etc. Besides artificial intelligence, we deeply honour the value in emotional and human intelligence presented by our dedicated teammates. Cultivating a healthy, joyful working environment fuels our mission towards establishing a successful, long-lasting partnership with one another. Join a collaborative and supportive team that continuously learns and grows together towards a common goal- creating a better, progressive future for everyone.
</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On March 22nd, Incodeks once again proved its commitment to the Tech Industry by offering young Computer Science students the opportunity to practice their coding skills under the mentorship of our professionals.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A quick guide on building a WhatsAPP Chat Bot with DialogFlow</title><link href="http://incodeks.com/guide-on-building-whatsapp-chatbot-with-dialogflow/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A quick guide on building a WhatsAPP Chat Bot with DialogFlow" /><published>2021-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://incodeks.com/guide-on-building-whatsapp-chatbot-with-dialogflow</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://incodeks.com/guide-on-building-whatsapp-chatbot-with-dialogflow/"><![CDATA[##### Introduction

I am Arlind Kerqeli, I have been working as a Software Engineer at Incodeks for more than 3 years now. As many of us know, Dialogflow on June 6  2020, has stopped the integration of many platforms that it had automatically, and from now on the implementation of these integrations has shifted to an open source. The purpose of this article is to set up an integration deployment to connect your existing Dialogflow agent with Twilio chat service platform. If you are a developer who uses Dialogflow to create different Dialogflow Agents who communicate with WhatsAPP, then you will definitely need this article.

If you do not have an existing Dialogflow agent, you can set one up by reading the documentation <a href="https://cloud.google.com/dialogflow/docs/" target="_blank">here</a>

##### Initial Setup
Setting up G Cloud CLI

The deployment process for GCP Cloud Run via this article utilizes G Cloud CLI commands. Follow the steps below to set up G Cloud CLI locally for this deployment.

1. On the G Cloud CLI <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sdk/docs/quickstarts">documentation page </a>, select your OS and follow the instructions for the installation.
2. Run G Cloud config get-value project to check the GCP Project configured.
3. Go into the Dialogflow agent’s settings and check the Project ID associated with the agent. The GCP Project configured in the G Cloud CLI should match the agent’s Project ID.
4. If the project IDs do not match, run G Cloud config set project PROJECT-ID, replacing PROJECT-ID with the Project ID from step 3.


##### Service Account Setup (GCP)
For the integration to function properly, it is necessary to create a Service Account in your agent’s GCP Project. See this page of the documentation for more details.
<br>
Follow the steps below to create a Service Account and set up the integration.
<br>
1. Go into the Dialogflow agent’s settings and click on the Project ID link to open its associated GCP Project.
2. Click on the navigation menu in the GCP console, hover over "IAM & admin", and click "Service accounts".
3. Click on "+ CREATE SERVICE ACCOUNT", fill in the details, and give it the "Dialogflow Client API" role.
4. Click on "+ Create Key" and download the resulting JSON key file.
5. Save the JSON key file in the twilio platform subdirectory.
<br>
<br>
If deploying this integration outside of GCP Cloud Run, it may be necessary to set the GOOGLE_APPLICATION_CREDENTIALS environmental variable on the deployment environment to the absolute path of the Service Account JSON key file. See this guide for details.

#####  Deploying the Integration
###### Setup

1. Go into the Dialogflow agent’s settings and click on the Project ID link to open its associated GCP Project.
2. Click on the navigation menu in the GCP console and click "Billing". Set up and enable billing for the project.
3. Enable Cloud Build and Cloud Run API for the project here.
4. Clone this git repository onto your local machine or development environment: git clone https://github.com/GoogleCloudPlatform/dialogflow-integrations.git
5. Open the root directory of the repository on your local machine or development environment.

##### Dockerfile and Creating the Build

Open the <a href="https://github.com/GoogleCloudPlatform/dialogflow-integrations/blob/03676af04840c21c12e2590393d5542602591bee/Dockerfile#L9" target="_blank">Dockerfile </a> in the root directory of the repository, and change YOUR_INTEGRATION in the following line to “Twilio”
<br>
<br>
   ENV INTEGRATION=YOUR_INTEGRATION  → ENV INTEGRATION=twilio
   <br>
<br>
If you have not done so already, copy your Service Account JSON key file to the Twilio platform subdirectory.


##### Twilio (Text Messaging) Integration
###### Setup Prerequisites

1. Create a <a href="https://www.twilio.com/try-twilio" target="_blank">Twilio account.</a>
2. Replace the value of projectId in the server.js file with your Dialogflow agent’s Project ID.

###### Retrieving Credentials

1. Log in to the <a href="https://www.twilio.com/console">Twilio Dashboard.</a>
<br>
2. Under the "Project Info" section, take the values for Account SID and Auth Token and replace the value for accountSid and authToken in the <a href="https://github.com/GoogleCloudPlatform/dialogflow-integrations/blob/03676af04840c21c12e2590393d5542602591bee/twilio/server.js#L34-L35" target="_blank">server.js</a> file respectively. 
<br>
<img src="/assets/posts/unnamed11.png" style="width: 100%;height: 400px; object-fit:contain">

##### Deploying the Integration Using Cloud Run

In your local terminal, change the active directory to the twilio root directory.

Run the following command to save the state of your repository into <a href="https://console.cloud.google.com/gcr/" target="_blank">GCP Container Registry.</a> Replace PROJECT-ID with your agent’s GCP Project ID.
<br><br>
G Cloud builds submit --tag gcr.io/PROJECT-ID/dialogflow-twilio
<br><br>
Deploy your integration to live using the following command. Replace PROJECT-ID with your agent’s GCP project Id and YOUR_KEY_FILE with the name (not path) of your Service Account JSON key file.
<br><br>
G Cloud beta run deploy --image gcr.io/PROJECT-ID/dialogflow-twilio --update-env-vars GOOGLE_APPLICATION_CREDENTIALS=YOUR_KEY_FILE 
--memory 1Gi

1. hen prompted for a target platform, select a platform by entering the corresponding number (for example, 1 for Cloud Run (fully managed)).
2. When prompted for a region, select a region (for example, us-central1).
3. When prompted for a service name hit enter to accept the default.
4. When prompted to allow unauthenticated invocations press y.
5. Copy the URL given to you, and use it according to the README file in the given integration's folder.



##### Setting up Phone Number
1. In the "Phone Number" section, go to Active numbers.
2. Click on the purchased number.
3. Underneath "Messaging", take the value for the server URL printed in the console after the completion of the execution of the last command from the above section to the "A message comes in" fill-in box. Set the first drop-down to Webhook and the HTTP method to HTTP POST.
<img src="/assets/posts/unnamed12.png" style="width: 100%;height: 250px; object-fit:contain">
<br><br>
If you don't understand anything or need help with this article please contact arlind@incodeks.com.
<br><br>
Thank you for your attention.

 

 
##### Author: Arlind Kerqeli]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The purpose of this article is to set up an integration deployment to connect your existing Dialogflow agent with Twilio chat service platform. If you are a developer who uses Dialogflow to create different Dialoglow Agents who communicate with WhatsAPP, then you will definitely need this article.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cognitive Virtual Assistants</title><link href="http://incodeks.com/personalized-oculus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cognitive Virtual Assistants" /><published>2021-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://incodeks.com/personalized-oculus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://incodeks.com/personalized-oculus/"><![CDATA[##### Author
I am Shpetim Sadriu working for Incodeks L.L.C as a Senior Software Engineer, experienced with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. 
I am writing this article because Cognitive Virtual Assistants (CVA) is advanced technology by the product business which is fundamentally a new sort of interaction between Hardware and Human Interaction. Cooperation concentrates in progress with a model on showing the legitimacy of the connection between communication, language and the disclosure of techniques to diminish the administration. This examination is offered another measurement to discover the source direction whose voice-recognition is made to be conceivable by the brainpower of Artificial Intelligence (AI).
Such a commitment to the paper comprises of: reviewing and summing up center thoughts from different orders, having the chance to see how much communication with Voice Recognition (VR) brings to the table; clarify why the objective with remote helpers is in the closer view; Defining the difficulties on the off chance that you need to offer more open doors for Cognitive Virtual Assistants (CVA) has been demonstrated below:


##### Introduction
<img src="/assets/posts/unnamed.jpeg" style="height: 500px; object-fit:contain">

<b>How DialogFlow works?</b>
1. A user sends a text/voice message to a device or an Application.
2. The message is categorized and matched to a corresponding intent (Intents
are defined manually by developers in DialogFlow)
3. DialogFlow agent reads text/voice and responds to input based on the
Intents. (This conversion from intent text responses to audio is known as
audio output, speech synthesis, text-to-speech, or TTS)
4. The App/Device transfers the message to DialogFlow.

<p><b>Google Assistant</b></p>
How to build Google Assistant using DialogFlow?
First of all sign-in Google &quot;Go to Action Console&quot; and click on &quot;New Project&quot;
<br>
<br>
<img src="/assets/posts/unnamed1.png" style="height: 300px; object-fit:contain">
<br>
<br>
Select your project name 'e-Shop', it should be unique due to your purpose. When you create the project you will be able to find templates or create from scratch your idea.
<br>
<br>
<div style="width: 100%;text-align: center">
<img src="/assets/posts/unnamed2.png" style="height: 100px; width: 100;object-fit:contain;margin: 0 auto" />
</div>
<br>
<br>
For this project I have chosen the "Health & Fitness" template, therefore we need to set up our actions. Go to <b>"Build your Action"</b> and <b>"Add Action(s)"</b>. 
Now we are going to create action by selecting Custom Intent and clicking the <b>"BUILD"</b> button.
<br>
<br>
<img src="/assets/posts/unnamed3.png" style="height: 400px;object-fit:contain;margin: 0 auto" />
 
Build your first Action
<br>
Build a custom conversational experience for the Google Assistant.
<br>
Now it is time to connect with DialogFlow go to console, and create a new project. 
<br>
<img src="/assets/posts/unnamed4.png" style="height: 400px;width: 100%;object-fit:contain;margin: 0 auto" />
<br>
In the DialogFlow tab you will be able to see on the left panel, Intents, Entities, Knowledge, Fulfillment, Integrations and so on.
<b>Responses</b> and delete Text Responses by creating your own. For example, i have written: "Welcome to e-Shop, Do you wanna hear more about nutritions?". 

Click Save, and let us create some follow-up intents as below, with "Yes"
<img src="/assets/posts/unnamed5.png" style="width: 100%;object-fit:contain;margin: 0 auto" />

<span style="color: red">Note:</span> "A <b>follow-up intent</b> is a child of its associated parent <b>intent</b>. When you create a <b>follow-up intent</b>, an output context is automatically added to the parent intent and an input context of the same name is added to the <b>follow-up intent</b>."
<br>
After Creating <b>"Follow-up Intent"</b> with response "Yes" click the row, go to response again, and add your response, for example: "Here are the best Nutritions: 1.Serious Mass, 2.MassTech, 3.Gold Weight", then click Save.
<br>
By adding different Follow-up, in the default or your own Intents, you will be able to have the best fit for your voice/chatbot virtual assistants project.

Once you write click Save button and go to Integration tab on the left panel side, then click <b>"INTEGRATION SETTINGS"</b>
<br>
<br>
<img src="/assets/posts/unnamed6.png" style="width: 100%;height: 400px; object-fit:contain;margin: 0 auto" />
<br><br>
Set "Auto-preview changes" to true, and click on Test, in order to see results.
<br>
<br>
<img src="/assets/posts/unnamed7.png" style="width: 100%;height: 400px; object-fit:contain;margin: 0 auto; margin-bottom: 2rem" />
<img src="/assets/posts/unnamed8.png" style="width: 100%;height: 400px; object-fit:contain;margin: 0 auto;" />
<br><br>
Results are shown above in the images, you can build your own bot and give different responses according to the topic you chose. 
When you create your own idea, now it is time to explain how to publish your voice/chat bot. 

<img src="/assets/posts/unnamed9.png" style="width: 100%;height: 400px; object-fit:contain;margin: 0 auto;" />

"Overview", and click "Decide how your Action is invoked", Choose a name for your Action, or type this name to begin interacting with it and click "Save" (Remember: name should be unique, and not existed before).
Go to "Overview", Get Ready for deployment,  --> Enter information required for the Actions directory, add necessary data, description, your logo and other informations. Invocation should be at least one selected in order users to be guided in the right way. Once you are done, click "Save".

<img src="/assets/posts/unnamed10.png" style="width: 100%;height: 400px; object-fit:contain;margin: 0 auto;" />
<br>
Go to "Overview", select the "Release" tab and then click on "Create a Release".

##### Author: Shpetim Sadriu]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As many of us know, Dialogflow on June 6 2020 will stop the integration of many platforms that it had automatically, and from now on the implementation of these integrations has shifted to an open source.]]></summary></entry></feed>